[ Music ]
[ 音乐 ]
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Hi, everybody.
大家好
My name is Ari Weinstein, and
我的名字是 Ari Weinstein
I'm really excited to be here
很高兴来到这里
along with Willem Mattelaer to
与 Willem Mattelaer 一起
tell you about Siri Shortcuts.
向大家介绍 Siri 的捷径
So, two years ago, we announced
两年前 我们发布了第一版 SiriKit
which enables your apps to work
让你的 App 能
with Siri, and it has great
使用 Siri 的功能
domain-specific knowledge for
它当时已经具备了
things like sending messages,
如发送信息
requesting rides, making
叫车 交易支付等
payments, and more.
诸多细化功能
But we know that you want to do
但我们知道
even more with SiriKit, and so
你想用 SiriKit 做更多的事情
that's why, this year, we're so
这也是为什么今年我们会
excited to announce Shortcuts.
如此兴奋地向大家介绍捷径
This central idea behind
捷径的核心思路
Shortcuts is that it lets you
是让你可以把自己的 App 中
expose the key capabilities of
最关键的功能
your app to Siri, and this is
与 Siri 接通
really great, because it enables
这样真的很好
people to use the features of
因为这让人们可以
your apps in new ways and in new
在新的场景以新的方式
places.
来使用你的 App
And it's a really powerful way
这是一种
to engage your users.
吸引用户的好方法
So, exposing a shortcut opens up
接通捷径
a ton of new possibilities for
为用户使用你的 App
how people can use your apps, so
开启了无数种可能性
let's explore all of the places
让我们一起看看可以使用
where Shortcuts can be used.
捷径的典型场景吧
Shortcuts takes Siri's
捷径通过
suggestions to the next level by
展示你接下来想要做什么
surfacing what you want to do
把 “Siri 建议”带到了一个新的层次
next, not just with your apps,
不仅仅是打开你的 App
but inside of your apps, and it
更能延伸到 App 内部的功能
does it by surfacing them in
并且 Siri 会在恰当的时机
search at just the right time.
在搜索界面中提供建议
And Siri can suggest shortcuts
Siri 还可以在 Apple Watch 上
on the Watch, so you can use
建议捷径
them right from your wrist on
你可以在你手腕上的 Siri 表盘
the Siri Watch Face.
上直接使用它们
When Siri is confident that it's
当 Siri 认为
the exact right time for a
应该使用某个捷径时
Shortcut, it will be surfaced on
它就会在锁定屏幕上
the lock screen.
显示建议
And, when you tap on a shortcut,
当你轻点一个捷径时
you can use it right in line
你直接在
with a rich custom UI specific
锁定屏幕上的定制 UI 上
to that app.
来使用它
And you can also add shortcuts
你还可以把捷径添加到 Siri
to Siri, so you can use them
这样你就可以
with your voice just by asking
通过询问 Siri
Siri.
来使用这些捷径
And in Siri you'll see the same
在 Siri 中 你会看到
custom UI that you see in search
与锁定屏幕和搜索界面中
and on the lock screen.
相同的定制 UI
And apps can provide a great
App 可以在 Siri 中提供
voice experience in Siri by
很好的语音体验
providing custom response dialog
App 提供自定义的响应对话
that Siri will read out loud to
而 Siri 会将其大声读出来
tell you things like how long it
来告诉你一些事情
will take for your coffee to be
比如咖啡还有多久做好
So, when the user adds a
当用户给 Siri 添加捷径时
shortcut to Siri, they get to
他们要先选择一个
pick a custom personal phrase,
自定义的个人短语
so the user chooses what to say
这样用户就可以选择
to Siri to invoke your shortcut.
对 Siri 说什么来启动捷径
And, as a developer, you get to
作为一个开发者
suggest what phrase to use, so,
你应该建议使用的短语
in this case, a suggestion is
在这种情况下 建议是“咖啡时间”
And, once a shortcut has been
一旦对 Siri 添加了一个捷径
added to Siri, it works across
这将在你所有
all of your iOS devices, and on
iOS 设备上
Apple Watch, and even on
在 Apple Watch 上 甚至在 HomePod 上都适用
So, we also have the new
我们也有新的
Shortcuts app, and with the new
捷径 App
Shortcuts app, anyone can build
通过这个新的捷径 App
their own shortcuts, and you do
每个人都可以打造自己的捷径
it just by dragging and dropping
需要做的只是拖拽和放下
a series of steps together.
一系列的步骤
And those steps can even include
这些步骤还包括
the shortcuts exposed by your
你 App 所接通的捷径
app.
我们今天将讨论
about how to adopt shortcuts for
如何在你的 App 中
your apps, and then we'll talk
使用捷径
about how to optimize your
以及如何优化你的捷径
shortcuts for great suggestions.
以提供更好的建议
And we'll also cover some
我们会讲到一些
privacy considerations that are
要特别注意的
important to keep in mind, and
隐私考虑
we'll talk about how to make
我们还会讲到
great shortcuts for media
如何为媒体播放 制作出色的捷径
So, first, we'll talk about how
首先 我们来讨论一下
to adopt the new Shortcut's
如何采用新的捷径 API
There were three steps for
创建捷径
creating a shortcut, and the
有 3 个步骤
first step is to define your
第 1 步是 定义捷径
That means you have to decide
这意味着你需要决定
what you want to expose as a
为哪个功能接通捷径
shortcut and define each one so
同时定义每个捷径
Siri knows everything that your
这样 Siri 就可以知道你的 App
app can do.
能做些什么
Next, you'll need to donate your
第 2 步 你需要递交（Donate）自己新的捷径
That means you need to tell the
这意味着每次用户
system every time the user does
在你的 App 中使用
something in your app that you
接通了捷径的功能时
expose a shortcut for, which
你都需要告诉系统
will let Siri learn when and
这样 Siri 才会习得
where is the right time to
建议你的捷径的
suggest your shortcut.
正确时机和场景
And the third step is to handle
第 3 步是处理你的捷径
That means, when the user wants
这意味着 当用户想要
to go and use your shortcut in
在 Siri 中 在锁定屏幕上
Siri, on the lock screen, in
或是在搜索界面使用你的捷径时
search, you need to be ready for
你需要准备好
your app or app extension to be
让你的 App 和 App 扩展
invoked and be handed the
可以被唤醒
shortcut to handle.
并将其传递至句柄
So, before you define shortcuts,
在你定义捷径之前
you'll need to decide what
你需要决定
exactly it is that you want to
你具体想要接通的功能是什么
And you should start by thinking
你需要考虑
through what are the most
什么是用户
important things that people
在使用你的 App 时
like to do with your apps?
会做的最重要的事
Because those are the things
因为这些事情
that you might want to consider
可能就是你需要
exposing shortcuts for.
接通捷径的东西
So, every shortcut that you
你接通的每一个捷径
expose should accelerate the
都应该让用户在使用
user, to perform a key function
你的 App 的核心功能时
of your app.
能有更快的速度
That means it should take
这意味着你应该采用一些
something that the user already
用户想用你的 App
wanted to do with your app and
所做的事情
help them do it even faster.
并让他们能更快地做这些事情
The acceleration that you offer
速度的提升应该
should be substantial, so you
是实质性的
shouldn't just expose a shortcut
你不能只是接通一个
that does about the same thing
正常地打开你的 App 的捷径
If you expose a shortcut that
如果你接通的捷径
doesn't provide very much
并没有让用户
acceleration to the user, it
在使用 App 时有很大的速度提升
won't be suggested as
那么它就不会被推荐为经常使用
And, next, every shortcut that
其次 每一个
you expose should be of
你接通的捷径
persistent interest to the user,
都应该能长期调动用户的兴趣
so that means it should be
这意味着
something that the user might
这应该是用户想要
want to do multiple times.
多次使用的功能
It's not a good idea to expose a
如果只是用户
shortcut for something that the
想要使用一次或两次的功能
user might only want to use once
那么为它们创建捷径
or twice.
不是什么好主意
And you should also expose only
你还应该只接通
shortcuts that are executable at
可以随时使用的捷径
any time, because you can't rely
因为在你的捷径准备好前
on the user being in some
你不能指望
particular state before your
用户处于某些
shortcut will be ready for use.
特定状态
So, once you've decided what
一旦你决定要
shortcuts to expose, you're
接通什么捷径时
ready to check out the
你就应该准备好查看
shortcuts' APIs.
捷径的 API
There were two APIs that we
我们有两种 API
support for adopting shortcuts.
来支持捷径的使用
The first is NSUserActivity.
第一种是 NSUserActivity
NSUserActivity is a lightweight
NSUserActivity 是一种代表你
way to represent the state of
App 状态的轻量级方式
your app, and it integrates with
它集成了一些
other Apple features like
其他的 Apple 功能
Spotlight and Handoff.
如“聚焦”和“接力”
And the second is intents.
第二种是 Intents
Intents are a way of
Intents 是
representing, in detail, a type
一种展示你的 App
of action that your app can
能实现的功能的方式
perform, and Siri includes a
Siri 内置了
bunch of great built-in intents
一系列很好的 Intents
that support a range of
它们支持一系列
capabilities that apps can use
App 可以用来
to integrate with Siri.
与 Siri 协作的功能
And, this year, we're
今年我们将
introducing something really
介绍一个非常酷的特性
cool, which is the ability for
你现在可以
you to define your own custom
自定义 Intents
intents for use with Shortcuts.
来与捷径协作了
So, for every shortcut you
因此 对于每一个你接通的捷径
expose, you'll need to decide
你都需要决定它
whether it should be an
是一个 NSUserActivity
NSUserActivity or an intent.
还是一个 Intent
So, let's talk about how to make
那么我们来谈论一下如何
that decision.
做出这个决定
Now, NSUserActivity is a great
目前 NSUserActivity 是
choice for building a shortcut.
构建捷径很好的选择
If you're just building a simple
如果你只是要构建一个
shortcut that opens something in
想要打开某些你 App 内的
your app, or if you're exposing
功能的简单捷径 或者你想要
a shortcut for something that
为某些你已经内置在“聚焦”搜索内
you already index in Spotlight
或者已经在 NSUserActivity 中
search, or that you already
提供的（比如“接力”）功能
offer in NSUserActivity for, for
接通捷径
example, for Handoff.
建议你选择 NSUserActivity
But for the best Shortcuts
但是如果想要最优的
experience, you'll want to adopt
捷径体验 你应该采用 Intents
intents, and intents-based
以 Intents 为基础的捷径
shortcuts are really cool,
真的非常酷
because they can run inline
因为它们不需要启动你的 App
without launching your app.
就可以内联运行
And they can include custom
它们能包含一些自定义的
voice responses and custom UIs
语音回复和定制化的 UI
like we saw earlier.
像我们刚刚看到的那样
And they can also include
它们还会包含一些
granular parameter predictions,
颗粒参数预测
which Willem tell you a little
这些 Willem 稍后
bit about later.
会和你们讨论
So, once you've decided how to
一旦你决定要采用哪种 API
adopt, you're ready to dive into
你就准备好
the implementation, so let's do
要开始实现了
that now.
那我们现在就开始
First, let's go over how to
首先 我们来看看
adopt shortcuts with
怎么用 NSUserActivity
NSUserActivity, and the first
来接通捷径
step is to define your shortcut.
第 1 步是定义你的捷径
For NSUserActivity, that means
对于 NSUserActivity 来说
you need to declare a
这意味着你需要
UserActivityType in your app's
在你 App 内的 Info.plist 文件中
Info.plist file to register your
声明一个 UserActivityType
activity type with the system.
来将你的 Activity 类型登记到系统中
Next, you need to donate your
接下来 你需要递交捷径
For NSUserActivity, that means
对于 NSUserActivity
every time the user is looking
这意味着每当用户处于
at the screen in your app that
你的 App 中你想提供
you want to provide a shortcut
捷径的界面时
to, you should make an
你都应该让你一个
NSUserActivity object available.
NSUserActivity 对象可用
So, there's one key new thing
这里有一个关键的新内容
isEligibleForPrediction flag.
就是 isEligibleForPrediction Flag
Setting this on any user
在任何 userActivity 上
activity turns it into a
把这个 Flag 设置为 “true”
shortcut, and what's really cool
都会把它变成一个捷径 真正酷的是
is if you have an existing user
如果你的 App
activity in your app, you just
已经有了一个 userActivity
have to set this to true and
你可以直接将这个 Flag 设置为 “true”
that user activity will become a
这个 userActivity 就会
shortcut automatically.
自动变成一个捷径
Now, note that the
请注意 isEligibleForSearch Flag 需要
be true in order for
设置为 “true”
isEligibleForPrediction to have
这样 isEligibleForPrediction
an effect.
才能生效
And, by the way, you might also
另外 你可能要考虑到
isEligibleForHandoff flag, which
isEligibleForHandoff Flag
defaults to true.
它的默认情况就是 “true”
So, by default, all of your user
所以在默认情况下
activities will be able to be
你的所有 userActivity
handed off between devices.
都可以在不同设备间“接力”
Now, when you're creating your
当你创建自己的 userActivity 时
user activity, you want to make
你要确保
sure to include all of the
包含所有
information in your user info
userInfo 词典中的信息
dictionary that you'll need to
以便之后
restore the activity later on.
可以还原在这个 Activity
And the last step is to mark
接着就是通过
your activity current by
把 userActivity 与当前屏幕上的
attaching it to a UI
UIViewController 或 UIResponder 连接
viewController or a UI responder
来标记你
object that's onscreen.
当前的 Activity
Now, the last step is to handle
最后一步就是 在定义
your shortcut, once you've
且递交了捷径之后
defined and donated it.
处理它们
And every time the user uses an
每次当用户从你的 App
NSUserActivity from your app, it
使用 NSUserActivity 时
will be opened in your app.
它都会在你的 App 中打开
And so you need to handle it by
你需要通过执行
implementing the app delegate
App 中用来处理
method for handling
NSUserActivity 的委托方法
NSUserActivity, which is called
即 continueUserActivity
continueUserActivity.
来对其进行处理
So, all you have to do is
你要做的就是
implement this method, check if
执行这个方法
the activity type matches the
确认这种 Activity 类型是否
one that you registered, and, if
与你所登记的类型匹配
it does, then you want to
如果匹配的话
restore the state of your app to
你可以将 App
what it was when the user
还原成 userActivity
activity was saved.
保存时的状态
So, that's everything you need
以上就是为了让
to do to get Siri to start
Siri 通过 NSUserActivity
suggesting shortcuts for your
为你的 App 建议捷径
apps with NSUserActivity.
你需要做的事情
Now, let's talk about how to
现在 让我们来谈论一下
expose Shortcuts through
如何通过 Intents 接通捷径
The first step, again, is to
第 1 步还是
define your shortcut.
定义你的捷径
And so with intents, you'll need
你可能需要
to start by deciding what type
从决定采用
of intent you'd like to adopt.
哪种类型的 Intents 开始
And, as you know, Siri includes
大家都知道 Siri 包含了
many great built-in intents,
很多内嵌很棒的 Intents
like for messaging, workouts,
比如信息 健身
lists, and more.
清单等等
And now we're introducing the
现在我们将介绍
ability to define custom intents
如何在 Xcode 中
in Xcode for Shortcuts.
为捷径定义自定 Intents
And so if the shortcut that you
如果你想要创建的捷径
want to build corresponds to one
正好与默认情况下的
of the default built-in SiriKit
内嵌式 SiriKit Intents 一致
intents, then you should adopt
那你应该采用它
But, otherwise, you can define
不过你也可以定义自己的捷径
And whether you want to define
不管你是想定义自己的 Intents
your own or adopt an existing
还是采用现有的
one to customize it, you want to
并对其进行定制
get started by creating an
你都需要在 Xcode 中创建
intent definition file in Xcode.
一个 Intents 定义文件
So, believe it or not, in my
在我的空闲时间
spare time, I've been working
我一直在与几个朋友
with a couple friends on a new
一起研发一个新的 App
app, and it's a soup delivery
这是一个送汤的 App
app, and it's called Soup Chef.
名字叫《Soup Chef》
It's the easiest way to order
要想订汤 使用这个 App
soup, and I'm really excited
再方便不过了 它与 Siri
about the potential of hooking
关联的潜力让我十分期待
So, let's step through how to
我们来看看怎样使用
use the new Intent Editor to
新的 Intent Editor
build an intent for Soup Chef.
来为《Soup Chef》创建一个 Intent
I'm going to start by going to
首先我将打开 Xcode 中的
File, New File in Xcode, and
“File（文件）”-“New File（新文件）”
I'll choose the SiriKit Intent
选择 “SiriKit Intent Definition File
Definition File type.
（SiriKit Intent 定义文件）”
And then I'll see the new Intent
然后我们就能看到全新的 Intent Editor
So, let's get started by
首先我们需要
clicking the plus button in the
点击左下角的加号按钮
Next, I want to give my intent a
接下来 我想给我的 Intent 取个名字
And, so in this case, I'm making
因为我要为订汤
an intent for ordering a soup,
制作一个 Intent
so I'm going to call it
所以我要称之为 “OrderSoup（订汤）”
Then I want to fill out my
接着我要填写
intent's metadata.
Intent 的元数据
So, let's look at that one step
让我们一步一步来看
The first piece of metadata is
第一个元数据是 “Category（类别）”
category and defining a category
定义 Category
helps Siri know how to talk
可以帮助 Siri 知道
about your intent and how to
如何讲述你的 Intent 以及
display it in the UI.
如何在 UI 上展示它
So, for example, in this case,
比如说 在这种情况下
I'm choosing the Order category,
我选择了 “Order（预定）”这个种类
and when I choose Order, Siri
如果我选择 “Order”
will say something like, "Okay,
当我使用到这个 Intent 的时候
I ordered it," when I use it
Siri 会说如 “好的 我预定了”这样的话
And it'll display a button
接着它会展示一个
confirmation title like Order.
如 “Order（预定）”的确认按钮
So, we offer several different
我们提供
categories, and you should
几种不同的类别
choose the one that matches your
你应该选择最适合
intent's purpose the most
你 Intent 目的
closely.
的那一个类别
Next, you want to fill out your
接着你要填写
intent's title and description,
Intent 的 “Title（标题）”
and that will be used in all the
和 “Description（描述）”
places where people can discover
这将会在各类场景中帮助用户发现
which shortcuts your app
你的 App 支持什么捷径
And then there's the User
然后就是 “User confirmation required
confirmation required checkbox,
（需要用户确认）”复选框
which determines whether or not
这将决定我们是否
we'll ask the user for a
在用户使用你的捷径前
confirmation before using your
询问他们是否确认使用
So, Siri might say something
所以 Siri 可能会说
like, "Are you ready to order
如“你准备好使用《Soup Chef》
with Soup Chef?"
来订汤了吗？”之类的话
That's really great for my app,
这对于我的 App 来说真的特别棒
because I want to make sure that
因为我想要确保用户
people aren't accidentally
并不是偶然地订汤 [ 笑声 ]
So, then, you'll see the intense
你可以在这里看到
parameters.
Intent 的 “Parameter（参数）”
And these define all of the
这里将会定义
parameters that are passed to
传递给你的捷径的所有参数
For example, in my case, I have
比如说 在我的例子里
two parameters.
我有两个参数
They are the list of items being
分别是被预定的汤品清单以及配送地址
Now, parameters support a short
目前 “Parameters” 支持一个
list of types, and those types
简短的类型列表
include things like string,
这些类型包括如字符串
number, person, and location.
数字 人物和位置等
But if you're building a
不过如果你想构建一个
parameter that represents an
能够代表你 App 中的对象
object that's in your app that's
但是却不在
not on the short list of types
类型列表中的参数
then you can choose the custom
那你可以
type.
选择 “Custom（自定义）”类型
Once you've defined your
当你已经定义好你的参数
parameters, you'll want to look
你可能会想要看一下
at shortcut types.
“捷径类型”
These define all of the types of
这里会定义
shortcuts that you'd like to be
你想要建议给用户的
suggested to the user.
所有捷径的类型
Each type includes a particular
每种类型都包含
combination of parameters that
一种特定的 会被预测的
will be predicted, and formats
参数组合 每一个类型
for how to display the title and
都标题和副标题的形式展示
subtitle of each one, filling in
其中会填上你的
the values for your parameters.
参数数值
So, if your shortcut can't be
如果因为你的捷径需要
performed in the background
启动你的 App 才能运行
because it needs to launch your
而导致的它不能在后台运行
app when you use it, you should
那么你可以不选
uncheck the Supports background
“Supports background
execution checkbox.
execution（支持后台执行）” 复选框
Now, in some cases, one intent
在某些情况下 一个 Intent
may have multiple shortcut
可能拥有很多个捷径类型
types, where some support
它们中有的支持
background execution and some
后台执行
don't.
有的则不支持
Now, in the case of Soup Chef,
在《Soup Chef》的例子中
that's especially relevant,
这尤其重要
because we can support
因为当预知了菜单和
background execution when both
配送位置后
the items and delivery location
我们可以支持后台执行
are predicted, because we have
因为我们拥有了
all we need to place an order.
下订单所需要的一切
But if we add a shortcut type
不过如果我们增加了一个
that only includes delivery
只包含配送位置的捷径类型
location, Siri may predict that,
Siri 会知道
and we won't actually have
我们可能不会有
enough information to place an
足够的信息来下订单
order.
所以我们需要启动 App
to ask the user what location to
来询问用户他们需要配送到
deliver to, and, in that case,
什么地址 在这种情况下
we'll want to not support
我们希望这种
background execution for that
捷径类型不要在
shortcut type.
后台执行
Now, you should specify shortcut
你应该列出
types for every variation of
你认为有助于 Siri
your shortcut that you think
做出最佳预测的
will be useful so that Siri can
捷径的每种变体的
make the best predictions.
捷径类型
And, for the best experience,
为了最佳体验
you should-- on all the shortcut
你应该尽可能
types, you can-- support
让所有的捷径类型
background execution.
都支持后台执行
Shortcut types that support
支持后台执行的
background execution provide
捷径类型让用户
more acceleration to the user,
体验速度更快
and so they'll actually be
这样它们会更频繁地被建议
You can provide up to 16
你可以为每个 Intent
shortcut types for every intent
提供最多 16 种你定义的捷径类型
Now, once your intent is
一旦你定义了你的 Intent
defined, Xcode will
Xcode 将
automatically code generate an
自动生成一个 Intent 类
intent class and an intent
和一个 Intent
handling protocol.
处理协议
In my case, we've generated the
在我的例子中
OrderSoupIntent class and an
我们生成了 OrderSoupIntent 类
OrderSoupIntentHandling protocol
还有一个 OrderSoupIntentHandling 协议
with properties that correspond
这个协议中有着与我刚刚
to what I just defined in my
在我的 Intent 定义文件中
intent definition file.
所定义的条目相一致的属性
Because Xcode is doing code
由于 Xcode 会自动生成代码
generation, it's really
很重要的一件事是需要考虑
important to consider in which
Xcode 在生成这段代码的时候
targets Xcode is doing this code
Target 是什么
generation, because you don't
因为你不想要
want to end up with duplicate
在最后呈现相同类当中
instances of the same classes
互相冲突的
that conflict with each other.
完全一样的实例
So, let's look at the targets in
让我们一起
the target membership section of
在 Inspector 面板中
the inspector on my intent
看看我的 Intent 定义文件中的
definition file.
“Target Membership（目标成员）”部分
Your intent definition file
你的 Intent 所使用的
should be included in every
每个 Target 都应该
target in which your intent is
包含你的 Intent 定义文件
used, so you should check the
你应该选中
box under Target Membership.
“Target Membership” 下面的复选框
But you'll want to make sure
不过你需要确定
that if you have a framework,
如果你拥有一个框架
you don't do code generation in
你不会在互相包含的
multiple targets that are
多个 Target 中生成代码
So, if you have a framework, set
如果你有一个框架
the target membership to only
你应该通过在每个 Target 中
generate intent classes for that
只选择 Intent 类
framework by choosing intent
而不选择生成的类
classes and choosing no
来将 “Target Membership” 设定为
generated classes for every
只为该框架生成 Intent 类
But if you don't have any
不过如果在你的 App 里
frameworks in your app because
没有任何框架
you haven't separated your app
因为你还没有将你的 App
into frameworks yet, you should
分离成框架
check the target for every
你应该为每一个 Target
single target.
检查 Target
And that's how you define custom
这就是如何在 Xcode 中定义
intents in Xcode.
自定 Intent
Once you've defined your custom
当你定义好了自定 Intent
intent, it's really easy to
想要递交就非常容易了
All you have to do is
你所需要做的只是
instantiate your intent object
将你的 Intent 对象实例化
and then populate its parameters
然后填入参数
and create and donate an
再创建并递交一个
INInteraction object.
INInteraction 对象
Make sure to do this every time
需要确保每次用户
the user performs the equivalent
在你的 App 中执行与你的捷径
of your shortcut in your app.
相同的任务时能做到这一点
In this case, every time the
在这种情况下 每次当
user orders soup, I want to
用户预订汤时
donate this intent, because
我就会递交这个 Intent
that's going to help Siri learn
因为这将帮助 Siri
when is the best time to predict
习得预测 Intent 的最佳时期
So, all that's left, now that
我们已经定义了自定 Intent
we've defined our custom intent,
现在要讨论的就是
is to handle it.
如何处理它
And, just like with
和 NSUserActivity 一样
NSUserActivity, you should
你应该在你的 App 委托里
continueUserActivity method in
执行 continueUserActivity 方法
your app delegate in order to
以此来处理
handle your intent.
你的 Intent
So, when an intent is opened in
当一个 Intent 在你的 App 中
your app, it's passed in as an
被打开时 它将以
NSUserActivity object, whose
NSUserActivity 对象的形式
activity type is the name of the
进入它的 Activity
intent class that you generated
类型就是之前你生成的
earlier.
Intent 类的名字
In this case, it's
在我的例子中
OrderSoupIntent.
就是 OrderSoupIntent
But if you only implement
不过如果你只执行
continueUserActivity, your
continueUserActivity
shortcut will open your app
你的捷径每次都会打开你的 App
It won't run in the background,
它不会在后台运行
or work inline in Siri, or
或者与 Siri 内联运行
support things like custom voice
也不会支持如自定声音
responses.
回复之类的功能
So, for the best experience, you
为了拥有最佳的体验
want to create an extension to
你想要创建一个在后台
handle your shortcut in the
处理你的捷径的拓展包
And to do that, create a new
要想实现这个目的
target in your Xcode project and
首先要在 Xcode 项目中创建一个新目标
choose the Intents Extension
然后选择 “Intents Extension
template.
（Intent 扩展）”模板
Make your intent handler conform
确保你的 Intent Handler
to the intent handling protocol.
遵循 Intent 处理协议
In this case, it's
在我的例子中
OrderSoupIntent handling and
就是 OrderSoupIntent 这个处理方式
then implement these methods,
然后再执行这些方法
which are confirm and handle.
也就是 confirm() 和 handle()
Now, note that unlike
需要注意的是
traditional SiriKit, you don't
和传统的 SiriKit 不同的是
need to implement any resolve
你不需要执行 resolve() 方法
methods, because your intent is
因为你的 Intent
ready to go without any
不需要任何
customization needed or any
用户定制或
follow-ups from the user.
用户的任何后续动作
So, in confirm, you should check
所以 你应该检查
all of the values of the
你 Intent 的属性的
properties of your intent to
所有数值以保证
make sure that they're valid.
它们是有效的
And, if they're not, you should
如果不是
return an error code if you
在你认为你不能处理
don't think you'll be able to
这个 Intent 的情况下
handle that intent.
你应该返回一个错误代码
And then you should handle,
然后处理 准确地说是
actually perform your shortcut.
执行你的捷径
So, in this case, that means
在我的例子中
actually placing an order for
这意味着为汤下订单
And then you return a response
接着你要返回一个
object that indicates the
能够指明结果
outcome, such as success.
如 “Success（成功）”的响应对象
Again, you should implement an
你应该为每一个 Target
intents extension for every
在后台运行的捷径
shortcut that can run in the
执行一个 Intent 拓展包
background, because then they'll
因为它们会
run right in line inside of
与 Siri 内部
Siri, on the lock screen, in
在锁定屏幕上
search, in the Shortcuts app,
在搜索界面中 在捷径 App 中
and on the Siri Watch Face,
或者是在 Siri 表盘中自动运行
without having to launch your
而不需要启动你的 App
The most valuable shortcuts are
最有价值的捷径
the ones that run in the
一定是在后台运行的
background, but you can also
不过你也可以创建
build a lot of great other
很多其他很好的捷径
And keep in mind that, even if
需要记住的是
you implement an intents
即便你执行了一个
extension, you should always
Intent 拓展包 你也应该一直
implement continueUserActivity,
执行 continueUserActivity
because the user will have the
因为用户可能会
opportunity to open the shortcut
通过 Siri 在你的 App 中
in your app from Siri, for
打开捷径
example, by tapping on the card
比如通过点击 Siri 上的卡片
in Siri that shows your apps'
来展示你 App 的
custom UI.
自定 UI
So, there's one more thing that
还有一件我想要
I want to tell you about, which
告诉你的事情
is INRelevantShortcut.
那就是 INRelevantShortcut
Now, INRelevantShortcut is the
INRelevantShortcut 是一种
way to expose shortcuts to the
向 Siri 表盘展示
Siri Watch Face, and you do it
捷径的方式
just by providing
你只需要提供
INRelevantShortcut objects that
包含 Intent
include your intents or user
或者 userActivity 的
activities.
INRelevantShortcut 对象即可
You can, optionally, include
你可以随意地
relevance information in your
在你相关的捷径中
relevant shortcuts, which is a
包含相关信息
hint to the Siri Watch Face as
这可以提示 Siri 表盘
to when your shortcuts will be
何时你的捷径是相关的
relevant and when's the best
以及什么时候是
time to show your shortcut?
展示你的捷径的最佳时期
Now, the really cool thing about
关于 INRelevantShortcut
INRelevantShortcut is that it
最酷的事情就是
works even if you don't have a
即便你没有 Watch App 它也能起作用
So, you can actually expose
你可以从你的 iOS App
relevant shortcuts from your iOS
接通相关的捷径
apps, and if they run in the
如果它们在后台运行
background, they'll appear right
就会直接出现在
on the Siri Watch Face.
Siri 表盘上
Okay, now that we've explored
好了 我们现在已经讲到了
all the ways that Shortcuts can
所有捷径的使用方法
be used and how to adopt the
以及采用 API 的方法
APIs, I'm going to turn it over
接下来的时间交给
to my colleague Willem who's
我的同事 Willem
going to give you a great demo
他将为你演示
of how to adopt shortcuts in
如何在 Xcode 中使用捷径 Willem
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Ari.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Ari
I'm so excited to be the first
我很兴奋能够成为演示
one to demo adopting Shortcuts.
如何使用捷径的第一个人
Before I dive into Xcode, let me
在我们深入 Xcode 之前
show you the app we've been
先让我向大家展示一下
working on.
我们一直在研发的一款 App
As Ari mentioned, we've been
正如 Ari 提到的
working on a soup-ordering app
我们在研发一款名为《Soup Chef》的
called Soup Chef.
订汤的 App
Let me show it to you.
让我来向你们展示一下
So, this is Soup Chef.
这就是《Soup Chef》
When I launch the app, I'm
当我启动这个 App 时
presented with my order history.
这里会展示我的订单记录
Since I haven't ordered anything
因为我还没有订过任何东西
yet, this is still empty.
所以这里还是空的
I can place a new order by
我可以通过点击加号
tapping the plus button.
来发出一个新的订单
This presents me with the soup
这为我展示了汤品的菜单
menu, where you can see the
在这里你可以看到
available soups I can order.
我能点的所有汤品
Let's order a tomato soup.
我们来点一个番茄汤
Next, I can specify the quantity
接下来 我可以选择
and options for my soup.
汤的数量和加料的种类
I'll order a single tomato soup
我要点一个有红辣椒的番茄汤
with red pepper, and when I'm
当我准备好下单时
ready to order, I tap the Place
我就轻点一下
Order button.
“Place Order（下单）”按钮
I'm brought back to the order
现在回到 “Order History（历史订单）”
history where you can now see
你就能看到我刚刚下的
the order that I just placed.
那个订单了
I can tap the order to see more
我可以轻点订单去看
details about a specific order.
关于一个特定的订单的更多细节
This view has an associated user
这一视图与 userActivity 相关联
I think it would be pretty cool
我认为将这个建议给用户
to suggest this to our users,
是非常好的
since our users like to
因为我们的用户喜欢
reminisce about the good soups
回味他们曾经点过的
they've ordered in the past
美味的汤
[laughter].
[ 笑声 ]
And it would be great if this
如果能把这些建议给她们
could be suggested to them.
那将非常棒
So, let's go to Xcode and see
让我们去 Xcode 看看
how we can do that.
如何实现这个设想
Here, I'm looking at the
现在我在观看
viewController for the order
订单细节视图的
detail view.
viewController
I'm creating a user activity,
我创建了一个 userActivity
and I'm setting the
同时我也设定了一个
requiredUserInfoKeys.
requiredUserInfoKeys
I'm also making sure that it's
我还要确保
EligibleForSearch.
isEligibleForSearch 为真
For it to be suggested, I also
为了它能够被建议
need to make it eligible for
我还需要让
prediction.
isEligibleForPrediction 为真
And that's it.
这样就行了 我们来试一下
First, I need to make sure that
首先我需要保证我
I donate the user activity, so
递交了 userActivity
I'll go back to the view.
我现在返回视图
That should be enough.
这样就够了
Now we want to make sure that
现在我想确保 Donation
the donation actually happened,
已经发生了
and, to do that, we added two
为了确认 我们增加
new developer settings that make
两项开发者设置
it super easy to see a recent
能让它在搜索界面和
donations in search and on the
锁定屏幕上很容易地看到
lock screen.
最近的 Donation
To enable it, I go to Settings,
为了启用这个
and I scroll down to the
我们来到“设置”
developer section.
滑动到“开发者”这一栏
At the bottom, there are two new
在最底端有两个新的开关
toggles, Display Recent
展示最近的捷径
Shortcuts and Display Donations
和在锁定屏幕上展示 Donation
Let's enable both.
我们打开两个开关
I can now go back to the home
现在我们可以回到主页面
screen and pull down to go to
下滑到搜索栏进行搜索
search, and I see the donation
我们可以看到
that I just did.
刚刚完成的 Donation 很好
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
I can tap it, and the app is
我可以轻点它 然后 App
launched with that user
就与 userActivity 一起启动了
activity, and I'm back to the
并且回到了我刚刚递交的
order that I was just donated.
订单页面
Great. So, this is pretty good,
很好 这样很赞
but I think we can do a lot
但是我认为我们还能做得更好
Since the main capability of our
因为我们 App 的主要功能
app is ordering soup, it would
就是订汤
be great if this could be
如果它能够把订汤建议给用户
suggested to our users.
那真是再好不过了
And I want users to be able to
我希望用户可以
do that without having to launch
不用启动我们的 App
the app.
就能达到这个效果
So, I'll implement it using an
我会使用一个 Intent 来实现
There isn't a built-in soup
现在还没有内置的订单 Intent
order intent, but now in iOS 12,
但是在 iOS 12 中
I can create a custom intent, so
我可以创建一个自定 Intent
I'll do that.
我们来试试
And to start by creating an
首先我们要创建一个
intent definition file, I'll go
Intent 的定义文件
to File, View.
先选择 “File(文件)”
File and select the SiriKit and
然后进入 “New（新建）”-“File...”
then definition file.
选择 “SiriKit Definition File"
Click Next.
然后 “Next（继续）”
Now I can give it a name.
现在我可以为它命名
I'll keep it to Intents, and
我会保留 “Intents” 这个名字
I'll put it in the Resources
然后放在 “Resources（资源）”文件夹里
group.
好了 现在我准备好了
I click Create.
点按 “Create（创建）” 这里展示的就是
definition file and our new
我们的 Intents 定义文件
Intent Editor.
以及我们的全新 Intents 编辑器
Before I add the intent, I'll
在我添加 Intent 之前
make sure to include the intent
我需要确保
definition file in the right
在正确的 Targets 内
targets.
包含 Intents 定义文件
As Ari said, we need to add it
正如 Ari 所说 我们需要
to all the targets where the
在使用 Intent 的所有地方添加 Target
So, I'll add it to our shared
所以我要把它添加在
framework, and, since we're
我们的共享框架中
using a shared framework, I
因为我们使用的是共享框架
don't want it to generate go for
我不想让它为 App Target 生成
So, in the dropdown, next to the
在下拉菜单中
app target, I'll select No
在 App Target 旁边
generated classes.
我会选择 “No Generated Classes
Now that that's done, we're
（无生成类）” 好了
ready to add our intent.
我们可以添加 Intent 了
I'll click the plus button in
在左下角点击加号
the lower left corner and select
同时选择
New Intent.
“New Intent（新建 Intent）”
I'll give it a name OrderSoup.
将其命名为 “OrderSoup”
Next, I'll select the category.
接下来我要选择类别
In this case, it's an order
在这个例子中
intent.
这是一个 “Order”Intent
Fill out the title, OrderSoup,
填写标题 “Order Soup”
and the description, Order a
然后是描述
soup from Soup Chef.
“在 Soup Chef 点一碗汤”
Since this involves a real-world
因为这涉及到真实世界的交易
transaction, I want to use it to
我想在提交
confirm this order before
订单前确认一下
placing it, so I'll select User
所以我会选择
confirmation required.
要求用户确认
Next, let's define the
接下来让我们定义参数
I'm going to define three
我将定义三个参数
parameters, one for the soup,
一个针对汤
one for the quantity, and one
一个针对数量
for the options that the user
还有一个针对用户选择的加料选项
I'll start with soup.
首先是汤 我点击 “Parameter” 部分的加号
parameter section and fill out
然后填写名字
the name, soup.
“soup（汤）”
Since soup is a custom object of
因为汤是我们 App 中的定制对象
our app, I'm going to select the
我将会选择
custom type.
“Custom（自定义）”类型
Next, I'll add quantity.
接下来 我要添加 “quantity（数量）”
I click plus again, fill out the
我再次点击加号 填写名字
name, and this is going to be an
这次将是一个
integer.
“Interger（整数）”类型
Next, options.
接下来是 “options（选项）”
Again, options is a custom
选项是我们的 App 的自定对象
object of our app, so I'll use
所以我会使用 “Custom” 类型
And since the user can select
因为用户可以选择
multiple options, I'll also
多个选项 我还会选中
check the array checkbox.
“Array（数组）”复选框
Finally, we need to define the
最后 我们需要定义捷径类型
At this point, I'm just going to
此时 我将定义一个
define a single shortcut type
包含了所有参数的单一的捷径类型
I'll click the plus button in
我会在“捷径类型” 中
the shortcut type section and
点击加号
select the parameters I want to
然后选择我想要包含在
include in the shortcut type, so
捷径类型中的参数
I'll select soup, quantity and
这样我就能选择汤数量选项了
When I'm ready, I click the Add
当我准备好时 点按“添加
Shortcut Type button.
捷径 类型”按钮
I fill out the title Order, and
填写标题订单
then I'm going to insert the
然后再插入 “quantity”
quantity and the soup with
以及 “soup” 和 “options”
options, and I'll leave the
然后我把副标题留白
already conveyed all the
因为在标题中
information I need to in the
我已经包含了需要的所有信息
I'll also leave Support
我还会选中 “Supports background
background execution checked,
execution（支持后台执行）”
because I want the user to run
因为我想让用户在后台
this intent in the background.
执行这个 Intent
So, we just defined our first
我们已经定义了我们第一个 Intent
Let's start using it.
现在让我们来试试
I'll start by adding two helper
首先我会为我们的 Order 对象
methods to our order object to
增加两个辅助方法
make it easier to convert
让它能更简单地
between it and the intent.
在它和 Intent 之间转换
I'll go to the order class and,
我现在来到 Order 类
at the bottom, I'll add an order
在最底端 我会增加一个 Order 扩展
It contains a computer variable
它包含一个
that returns an intent.
可以返回 Intent 的系统变量
In it, I create the intent.
我在这里创建 Intent
I set the soup quantity and
设定汤的数量和
options, and I return the
选项 然后返回到 orderSoupIntent
Extension also defines a new
扩展同样也定义了
initializer that dates an
一个新的源于 Intent 的
intent.
初始化程序
In it, I extract the soup,
在这里 我抽取汤
quantity, and options, and then
数量 和选项
I initialize the order with
然后我用这些数值
those values.
初始化订单
Great, this will be very
很好 这会非常有用
Next, we need to make sure that
接下来 我需要确保
we donate the intent every time
每次用户下订单的时候
the user places an order.
我们都递交了 Intent
So, I'll go to the soup order
所以我来到订汤的
data manager, and, in the
数据管理器
placeOrder method, I'll add our
在 placeOrder() 方法中 我会添加
donation logic.
我们的 Donation 逻辑
I create an INInteraction that
我声明了一个 INInteraction
contains the intent of the
它包含了订单的 Intent
order, and then I just donate
然后递交
that interaction, and that's it.
interaction 就好了
Finally, we need to handle the
最后 我们需要处理 Intent
I'll start by adding support in
首先我需要在 App 中
the app itself, so I'll go to
增加支持
the AppDelegate, and, in the
我们打开 AppDelegat.swift
continueUserActivity, I'll add
在 continueUserActivity 中
support for it.
我会为其增加支持
I check if the activityType of
我想要确认 userActivity 的
the userActivity is equal to the
activityType 是否与我想
class name of the intent that I
处理的 Intent 的类名称一致
If that's the case, I extract
如果一致
the intent from the
我会从 userActivity 中提取
userActivity, and I generate an
Intent 同时生成
order with it.
一个 Intent
Finally, I present the order
最后 我会展示订单视图
So, since we're launching the
既然我们打开了 App
app, I'm assuming that the user
我假设用户并不想
doesn't want to immediately
立刻下订单
place the order but wants to
而是想在下订单之前
make some customizations before
做一些定制
placing it, so that's why I'm
这就是我展示订单视图的原因
And, finally, let's add support
最后 让我们增加对
with an intents extension so the
Intent 扩展的支持
user can run this intent in the
这样用户就可以在后台
background.
运行 Intent 了
I'll need to add an intents
首先我需要增加一个
extension first, so I'll go to
Intent 扩展
File, View, Target and select
选择 “File”-“New”“-Target”
the Intents Extension target.
然后选择 “Intents Extention
I'll give it a name,
（Intents 扩展）” 我要为它起个名字
SoupChefIntents, and I click
SoupChefIntents 然后点按 “Finish（完成）”
Since I've added a new target
因为我增加了一个我可以使用
where I'll use the intents, I
Intent 的新 Target
need to make sure that the
我需要确保
intent definition file is
Intent 定义文件
included in that target.
被包含在 Target 中
So, I go back to the intent
回到 Intent 定义文件
definition file and add it to
然后将其增加到 Target 中
Again, I don't want to generate
我还是不想在 Target 中
code in that target, so, in the
生成代码
dropdown, I'll select No
在下拉菜单中 我选择
generated classes.
“No Generated Classes”
I also want the extension to
我还希望扩展 Target 能
have access to the same data as
接入 App 的相同数据
the app, so I'll add it to the
所以我会将其增加到
same app group.
相同的 App 群组
In the Project Settings, I
在项目设定中
select the intents target and in
我选择 Intents Target
the capability step, I'll add it
在 “Capability” 页中 我会将其添加到
to the same app group.
相同的 App 群组
Great. Now, we're ready to
很好 现在我们就可以
implement the intent handler
执行与这个 Target
that was created with this
相匹配的 IntentHandler 了
First, I'll import our shared
首先 我要引入我们共享的
framework, SoupKit [laughs].
框架 SoupKit [ 笑声 ]
Since we're going to handle the
因为我们将处理
OrderSoupIntent, this intent
OrderSoupIntent
handler needs to conform to the
这个 IntentHandler 需要
OrderSoupIntentHandling
与 OrderSoupIntentHandling 协议相一致
This was generated as part of
它是作为我们 Intent 的一部分生成的
This protocol has one required
这个协议有一个必要的方法
method, the handle method.
也就是 handle() 方法
Let's implement it.
让我们实现它
In the handle method, I get an
在 handle() 方法中
intent.
我得到了一个 Intent
I create an order from that
我通过那个 Intent 创造了一个订单
intent, and, if that succeeds, I
如果成功了
place the order, and I call the
我就下了订单
completion with an intent
我就会调用 completion()
response with a success code.
其中会有 Intent 的响应码 “.success”
If I'm unable to create an order
如果我不能从 Intent 中
from the intent, I call
创造一个订单
completion with an intent
我也会调用 completion()
response with a failure code.
但是其中的 Intent 响应码会变成 “.failure”
And that's it.
就是这样
I've just added support for a
我刚刚在我的 App 里
new intent in my app.
为一个新 Intent 添加了支持
Let's try it out.
让我们尝试一下
First, I'll need to donate the
首先 我需要递交 Intent
intent.
我会下另一个订单
Click the plus button and this
点击加号
time I'm going to order a clam
这次我要订一个有面包丁的
chowder with croutons, and I'll
蛤蜊浓汤 我要下单了
Now, if we go back to the home
现在 如果我重新回到主屏幕并下滑
screen and pull down, I see my
我可以看到我递交的 Intent 很好
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
I can tap it, and I'm presented
我可以点击它
with a shortcut view and the
现在展示的是一个捷径视图
order button.
以及 “Order（点餐）”按钮
If I tap the order button, the
如果我点击它
order will be placed in the
就会直接在后台下单
background, and it's ordered.
这样订单就完成了
I can go back to the app and see
我可以回到 App
if it was actually ordered, and,
看看它是否预订上了
yeah, there is a new order in my
是的 在我的 App 里有一个新订单
Great, so easy.
很好 很简单
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
I can also, instead of tapping
除了轻点“点餐”按钮
the order button, tap the
我还可以点击
shortcut view, itself, which
捷径视图本身
will launch the app with the
这将会通过捷径启动 App
shortcut, and, as I implemented
由于我实现的方法
it, it shows the order view,
它将会展示订单视图
where I can customize the order.
这里我可以自定义订单
So, I'll add cheese, too.
我还可以加上奶酪 谁知道呢
And I'll place the order.
我要下单了
Great. Finally, let's add the
很好 最后 让我们给 Siri
shortcut to Siri.
加上捷径
I'll go to Settings, and I
我们来到设置
scroll up to the Siri and
向上滑到 “Siri 与搜索” 搜索
Here I can select the shortcut
这里我可以选择我想要添加到 Siri 的捷径
In this case, I'll add the order
在这个例子中 我要添加
one clam chowder with croutons.
预定一份带面包丁的蛤蜊浓汤
When I tap the record button, I
当我选择录音按钮时
can say the phrase I want to
我可以说出我想与这个捷径
associate with the shortcut.
相关联的短语
Soup time.
“Soup time（喝汤时间）”
Now, they got it.
这样就好了
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
Let's take a step back and look
让我们回顾一下
at what we just did.
我们刚刚所做的
We started by making an
我们首先让一个
NSUserActivity that was already
已经在我们 App 中实现的
implemented in our app eligible
NSUserActivity 中的
for prediction.
isEligibleForPrediction 为真
This allowed it to be suggested
这让其可以被建议
and is a really easy way to
同时也是一个接通你 App 内容的
expose the content of your app.
简单的方法
Next, we defined a custom
接下来 我们定义一个自定 Intent
This is really the best way to
这真的是展示
represent a piece of key
你的 App 的核心功能的
functionality of your app.
最好方法
In our case, that was ordering a
在这个例子中 就是点一碗汤
After defining the intent, we
定义好 Intent 之后
made sure that we donate the
我们要确保每次用户在
intent every time the user
App 内下单时
placed an order inside of the
我们都递交了 Intent
app.
最后 我们处理 Intent
intent, both in an extension to
不仅是在支持后台运行的
support background execution and
扩展 Target 中的
in the app itself so the user
还有在 App 内的
can launch the app with the
这样用户就可以
shortcut.
通过捷径 启动 App
So, now that we've seen how you
现在我们看了如何
can adopt shortcuts, let's take
采用捷径
a look at how those shortcuts
接下来我们看看这些捷径 是如何
are suggested and what you can
被建议的以及你可以做些什么
do to make sure your users see
让你的用户看到
the best possible suggestions.
可能的最佳建议
Every time a user performs an
每次当一个用户在你的 App 内
action in your app and your app
完成一个动作并且
donates this, the system will
你的 App 递交了这个动作
look at the time, location, and
在这个例子中 就是和其他信息
For a time, we consider, among
对于时间 我们认为
other things, the time of day
应该记录一天中的时间
and the day of the week.
或一周中的一天
Well, for the location, we look
至于位置
at the overall location of the
我们会看看用户的
user and see if it's a
整体位置 然后确定
significant location for that
这是否对于用户来说是一个重要的位置
Let's see how the system now
接下来看看系统如何
uses these to make a suggestion.
利用这些来做出建议
Here, we'll just consider the
在这里 我们只考虑时间
Monday, at lunch, I order a
周一 午饭时间 我预定了一份
tomato soup with croutons.
加面包丁的番茄汤
That evening, I don't feel like
晚上的时候我不喜欢面包丁
croutons, so I order a tomato
所以我预定了一份
with red pepper instead.
加红辣椒的番茄汤
Next day at lunch, I, again,
第二天的午饭 我再次
order a tomato soup with
预定了加面包丁的番茄汤
I keep doing this throughout the
我一整周都这样操作
week, and, on Friday, at lunch,
在周五午饭的时候
Siri might try to find a
Siri 可能会尝试给我建议
It will look at my past behavior
它会观察我过去的行为
and try to find a pattern in it.
尝试在里面找到规律
And since it's lunchtime, and I
如果现在是午餐时间
usually order a tomato soup with
由于我经常在中午预定
croutons at lunchtime, Siri
加面包丁的番茄汤
might notice this and suggest
Siri 可能会注意到这点并向我建议
this to me, which is great.
这样很好
It's exactly what I wanted.
这就是我想的
So, this is all pretty high
这些都是很高层级的东西
level, so let's take a look at
我们来看看
how it actually works, starting
它是如何工作的
with NSUserActivity.
我们先从 NSUserActivity 开始
Imagine a user activity for the
我们假设一个在《Soup Chef》中
place order screen in Soup Chef.
下单界面的 userActivity
The user info dictionary could
用户信息字典可能包含三个 Key
quantity, and scroll position.
“soup” “quantity” 和 “scrollPosition
The last one is there, so, in
（滚动位置）” 由于最后一个的存在
Handoff, you can bring the user
在“接力”中 你可以将用户
back to the exact position they
带回到他最后所浏览的那个位置
Let's take a look at how this
我们看看这要怎么
can be suggested to the user.
建议给用户
We start by donating a user
首先我们递交一个
activity where the soup is
NSUserActivity
tomato, the quantity is 1, and
其中汤是 “tomato”
the scroll position is 79
数量是 “1”
points.
滚动位置是 “79.0”
Next, we donate a similar user
接下来我们递交一个相似的
activity, but now scroll
NSUserActivity
position is changed to 110
但是滚动位置
points.
却变成了 “110.0”
We keep doing this, and, at some
我们继续操作 在某一时刻
point, Siri will try to find a
Siri 可能会再次试着寻找一个建议
It will look at past behavior
它会查看过去的行为
and try to find a pattern of
然后寻找相同的
equal user activities.
NSUserActivity 的规律
But since the scroll position is
由于滚动位置每次都不一致
might not be able to find a
它可能不会找到合适的建议
So, how can we fix this?
那我们要如何修复呢
We can use the
我们可以使用
requiredUserInfoKeys.
requiredUserInfoKeys
RequiredUserInfoKeys is an
requiredUserInfoKeys 是一种
existing property of a user
NSUserActivity 的现有属性
It represents the minimal amount
它代表了为了复原 App 到
to restore the app to the state
userActivity 展示的状态
that the user activity
所需的最少的信息数量
And for suggestions it will be
至于建议
used to determine which keys of
它会被用来指定
the user info dictionary will be
用户信息字典中哪些关键信号
used to compare when looking for
会在寻找规律时用来进行对比
Let's apply this to a previous
让我们将其应用在
example.
刚刚的例子中
Now we specify that
现在我们可以注明
requiredUserInfoKeys are soup
requiredUserInfoKeys 是汤和数量
Again, we donate the user
我们再次递交
activity where the soup is
汤是 “tomato”
tomato, the quantity is 1, and
数量是 “1”
the scroll position is 79
滚动位置是 “79.0” 的 userActivity
But now the scroll position will
不过这次滚动位置将被忽略
Next, we donate something
接下来 我们递交一些
similar, and, again, the scroll
相似的东西 这些滚动位置
position is ignored.
也被忽略了
We keep doing this, and, at some
我们一直重复 在某些时刻
point, Siri will try suggestion
Siri 会再次尝试推荐
Now, I will look back and try to
现在 Siri 会回顾
find a pattern of equal user
然后试着为相似的 userActivity 寻找一个规律
And since it's no longer
因为不再考虑
considering the scroll position,
滚动位置
it might be able to say, "An
她可能会想
NSUserActivity with soup tomato
“一个汤是 ‘tomato’ 数量是 ‘1’ 的
and quantity 1 is a good
NSUserActivity 可能对这个用户来说
suggestion for this user."
是一个不错的建议”
So, as you just saw, it's really
如你所见
important to specify the right
根据需求标明
set of keys as being required.
正确的关键元素很重要
Otherwise, your users might not
否则你的用户可能
get any suggestions at all.
不能获得任何建议
So, that's how it worked for
这就是它如何与
user activity.
userActivity 协作的
Intents work similarly but offer
Intent 的工作原理与这个相似
you a lot more flexibility.
但是却更加灵活
The main signal for intents are
Intent 的主要信号是
the shortcut types that you
你定义的捷径类型
Each shortcut type defines a
每一种捷径类型
combination of parameters that
都定义了
is valid for suggestion.
对于建议来说有效的参数组合
It's similar to the
这与 requiredUserInfoKey
requiredUserInfoKeys, but
有点相似
instead of having just one set,
但是与其只有一个组相比
you can define multiple.
我们在这里可以定义多个
Let's apply this to our Soup
让我们在《Soup Chef》App 中
Chef app.
应用一下
Earlier, I defined an
早些时候 我通过三个参数
OrderSoupIntent with three
即 “soup” “quantity” 和 “options”
parameters, soup, quantity, and
定义了一个 OrderSoupIntent
At the time, I only defined a
当时 我只定义了
single shortcut type that
一个包含所有这些参数的单一的捷径类型
parameters, but, ideally, you
但是 理想地说
would define more shortcut
你可以定义更多捷径类型
types, since that gives more
因为这能为系统
options to the system to find
寻找用户行为的规律提供了更多选择
So, now I'll define three.
现在我要定义三个
One shortcut type that combines
一个捷径类型结合了
soup and quantity, one that
“soup” 和 “quantity”
combines soup and options, and
一个结合了 “soup” 和 “options”
one that combines all three
还有一个结合了三个参数
Let's apply this to another
让我们在另一个例子中看一看
Again, I start on Monday, at
我再次从周一开始
lunch, by ordering a tomato soup
在午餐时间
with croutons.
点一个加面包丁的番茄汤
The Soup Chef app donates this
《Soup Chef》将这个递交给系统
to the system, and the system
然后系统将会
will split us up into all the
根据我刚刚定义的
possible combinations based on
捷径类型
the shortcut types that I just
将把它分成
defined.
所有可能的组合
That evening, I order a tomato
当天晚上 我点了一份
soup with red pepper.
加红辣椒的番茄汤
Again, it gets donated, and it
它再次被递交
will be split up in all the
也被分解成所有
possible combinations.
有可能的组合
Next day, at lunch, I order a
第二天的午饭 我点了一份
tomato soup with croutons.
加面包丁的番茄汤
It gets donated and split up.
它被递交并分解
I keep doing this throughout the
我整周都重复这个操作
week, and, on Friday, at lunch,
在周五的午餐时间
Siri might try to find a
Siri 可能会尝试对我建议
It might see that I often order
它可能会看到
a single tomato soup.
我经常点番茄汤
But since it's lunchtime, it
不过因为是午餐时间
also can see that, at lunchtime,
它也能看到在午餐时间
usually order a tomato soup with
我通常会在番茄汤里加面包丁
Since that is a more specific
这是一个更具体的捷径
shortcut, it will end up
它最后会
preferring to suggest that.
这样建议
So, I might get a suggestion to
所以我可能会被建议
order a tomato soup with
点一份加面包丁的番茄汤
Great. So, that's how
很好 这就是如何
suggestions are made.
完成建议
Let's now take a look at how to
现在让我们看看
make sure those suggestions are
如何确保这些推荐是好的
good, and it all starts from
首先需要做的是
making good donations.
有一个好的 Donation
A good donation should be
一个好的 Donation
something that is likely to be
应该是一些很大概率重复的东西
For user activity, there could
对于 userActivity 来说
be some content they might look
应该是一些用户经常查看的内容
Or, for an intent, there could
或者对于 Intents 来说
be an action the user would take
应该是一些用户会规律做出的动作
You should make sure that the
你应该确保
payload of what you're donating
你递交的载荷
is consistent across all your
与你所有的 Donation
donations, since that is what
都是相一致的 因为这是
will be compared when looking
系统在寻找规律时
for patterns.
对比的东西
A good donation should also not
一个好的 Donation 应该不仅包括
include a timestamp, since that
时间标记
might not longer be relevant by
因为当这个 Donation 被推荐时
the time this donation would be
它可能不会再与
suggested.
特定时间相关
For instance, a shortcut that
比如说 一个展示
shows appointments for a
某个特定日期的会议的
specific day is probably not
捷径可能没那么有用
that useful, since, if you see
因为 如果你第二天
that the next day or later,
或者之后看到这个提醒
you're probably no longer
你可能对这个
interested in the meetings of
特定的一天的会面
that specific day.
不再感兴趣了
A shortcut with a relative time,
一个有着相对时间的捷径
however, is a lot more useful.
却更加有用
You should also make sure that
你应该确保
you donate exactly once for each
你为每一个用户行动
user action, even if that user
进行一次递交
action involves multiple actions
即便那个用户行动包括
inside your app.
在你 App 内多次的行动
Finally, selecting the correct
最后 为你的 Intent
parameters of your intent is
选择正确的参数也是非常重要的
So, let's take a look at two
所以我们来看一下
possible types, starting with
两种可能的类型
enums.
首先是枚举
You can define enums in your
你可以在 Intent 旁边的
intent definition file next to
Intent 定义文件中
your intents, and use it as the
定义枚举
types of your parameters.
并将其作为你参数的类型
We recommend that you use enums
我们建议每当
whenever the values for a
参数的数值有界时
parameter are bounded.
你都使用枚举
For instance, if you would add a
比如说 如果你想为
size parameter to a order soup
OrderSoupIntent 添加一个
intent, it might make sense to
规格参数 那么将其
make that an enum, since the
做成枚举可能会比较有意义
possible sizes are probably just
因为可能的规格一般是
small, medium, and large.
小份 中份 大份
Using an enum will lead to
使用枚举可以为你的用户提供
better suggestions and clearer
更好的建议和
titles and subtitles for your
更清晰的标题和副标题
To learn more about how enums
想要学习更多关于
are used to generate titles and
如何用枚举生成标题和
subtitles, I recommend that you
副标题的内容
watch the localization session.
我建议大家观看本地化讲座
Another type you can use is the
另一个你可以使用的类型是
custom type.
“Custom（自定）”类型
Using a custom type will result
使用自定类型最终会
in an INObject and your
得到一个 INObject
generated intent code.
并生成 Intent 代码
An INObject combines an
INObject 结合了
identifier with a display
一个标识符和一个显示字符串
The identifier can be used to
这个标识符可以用来
refer to an object internal to
指代你的 App 中的
your app, while the display
一个内部对象
string contains the user
显示字符串则包含
readable representation of that
一个标识符和一个代表形式
That way both your users and
这样你的用户和 App
your app always understands what
都可以知道
the value of this parameter is.
这个参数的数值是多少
Finally, using an INObject also
最后 使用一个 INObjec
prevents the possible dependency
也会防止参数之间
between parameters.
可能出现的依赖性
Let me illustrate that.
让我来示范一下
There are two ways to represent
总共有两种办法来
the combination of an identifier
代表拥有一个字符串的
with a display string.
标识符的融合
You could add two parameters to
你可以为你的 Intent
your intent, one for the
增加两个参数
identifier, one for the display
一个是给标识符
string, or you could add a
一个是给显示字符串
single parameter using the
或者你还可以使用 INObject 来增加单个
With the first approach, you
如果用第一种方法
have a dependency.
你会有一个依赖
Since the display string depends
因为显示字符串依赖于
on the object as referenced by
被标识符引用的对象
the identifier, we discourage
我们不鼓励这类
having these dependencies as
依赖的产生
they could cause issues when we
因为在我们之后建议 Intent 时
suggest this intent later.
这些依赖可能会引发问题
A good shortcut should also have
一个好的捷径还应该
an understandable title,
拥有一个可以理解的标题
subtitle, and image.
副标题 还有图像
It should represent what will
它应该展现当用户
happen when the user taps the
点击捷径时会发生什么
shortcut, since it will be the
因为这是用户在
only thing the user will see
与其互动前
before interacting with it.
看到的唯一的东西
And, of course, you want to test
当然了 你应该测试你的捷径
your shortcuts to make sure that
来保证它们
they look right and that they
看起来是正确的
behave as expected.
而且他们会像预期的
There are a couple of ways to do
那样工作
that.
有一些方法来做到这点
As I showed you earlier, we
正如我早些时候展示给你的
added two new developer settings
我们增加了两个新的开发者设置
that allow you to see your
可以让你在搜索界面
recent donations on search and
和锁定屏幕上
on the lock screen, instead of
看到你最近的 Donation
your regular Siri suggestions.
而不是你常规的 Siri 推荐
By enabling these, you can see
打开这个你就可以看到
what your users will see when
当这些 Donation 被建议时
those donations would be
你的用户会看到的东西
suggested, and you can try
你可以试着与其互动
sure that they behave as
这样就能保证
expected.
它能按预期工作
Another way to test your
另外一个测试你的
shortcuts is by adding them to
捷径的方法
Siri.
就是将其添加到 Siri
An easy way to test them then is
一个测试它们的简单方法就是
by editing the Xcode scheme to
通过编辑 Xcode Scheme
automatically invoke Siri
在不需要重复短语
without constantly having to say
的情况下
the phrase.
来自动唤醒 Siri
In the scheme editor of an
在 Intent 扩展的 Scheme 编辑器中
intents extension there is the
有一个 Siri Intent Query 栏
Siri Intent Query field that you
你可以用它来提供
to invoke Siri with.
唤醒 Siri 的语音
And, finally, you can create a
最后 你可以在捷径 App 中
custom shortcut in the Shortcuts
创建一个自定捷径
app that uses your shortcut.
来使用你的捷径
This allows you to test the
这允许你测试
behavior of your shortcut when
当你的捷径与从捷径 App
it's chained together with other
中的其他捷径
shortcuts or steps from the
或者步骤捆绑在一起的
Shortcuts app.
你的捷径的表现
So, now that we've seen what a
我们已经看到了
good shortcut donation is and
什么是好的 Donation
how does donation get suggested
以及如何向用户建议这个 Donation
to your users, let's take a look
我们再来看看一些
at a couple of privacy
关于隐私的考虑
considerations and how you can
以及如何确保
make sure your user are never
你的用户
upset by what is suggested to
不对给他们的建议感到失望
Your users expect that when they
你的用户希望当他们
delete something from within
从你的 App 中删除一些东西时
your app that it's deleted for
这个删除是永久的
It's important to honor this so
这一点很重要
you maintain your users' trust
这样你就可以获得你用户的信任
and your so users aren't
他们也不会
presented with suggestions for
再收到与他们想要的
things that are not relevant to
毫不相关的信息了
So, if you donate shortcuts that
如果你的捷径
contain information that the
包含一些用户可以删除的
user can delete, you should make
信息 你应该
sure to delete those donations
在合适的时间
at the appropriate time.
删除它们
Let's take a look at how to
我们来看看
delete donations, starting with
如何删除
NSUserActivity.
从 NSUserActivity 开始
There are two ways to delete a
有两种方法来删除一个
donated user activity.
已递交的 userActivity
If you use Spotlight indexing
如果你使用“聚焦”索引
and you set the
你可以设定
relatedUniqueIdentifier, then
relatedUniqueIdentifier
deleting the content from
然后从“聚焦”删除的内容
Spotlight will automatically
就会自动
delete the donated user
删除递交的
activity.
userActivity
Just set the
只需要在 contentAttributeSet 里
relatedUniqueIdentifier on the
将 relatedUniqueIdentifier
contentAttributeSet to the
设定为与可搜索的对象
item that it matches with.
相匹配的标识符
Then, when that searchable item
接着 当可搜寻对象被删除时
automatically delete the user
它会自动删除 userActivity
If you don't use Spotlight
如果你不使用“聚焦”索引
indexing, you can use the
你可以使用
persistent identifier property
NSUserActivity 中的
on NSUserActivity.
持续标识符属性
This is a new property that you
这是一个你可以设置的新属性
can set so you can keep track of
这样你就可以追踪你的
your user activities and delete
userActivity 并在合适的时间
them at the appropriate time.
删除它们
To use it, just set the
要想使用它
persistentIdentifier property
只需要在递交 userActivity 前
before donating user activity.
设定 persistentIdentifier 属性
Then, when you want to delete
如果你想要将其删除
it, you call
你可以调用
deleteSavedUserActivities with
deleteSavedUserActivities
the identifiers that you want to
并填入你想要删除的标识符
You can also delete all your
你还可以删除所有
donated user activities.
递交的 userActivity
For instance, when your user
比如说 当你的用户
logs out, you can do that by
退出登录时
calling
你可以调用 deleteAllSavedUserActivities
Intents have an existing API,
Intents 拥有现成的 API
which is similar to this new
与新的 userActivity
user activity API.
API 相似
Since you donate intents through
因为你通过 INInteraction 主导
INInteraction the leading and
Intent 的 Donation
donated intent also happens
删除 Intent 也会通过
through INInteraction.
INInteraction 发生
An INInteraction has an
一个 INInteraction 拥有一个
identifier and a group
标识符和一组
identifier property that you can
你可以设置的标识符性能
set and then later use to delete
然后用它来删除
one or more donated
一个或多个已经递交的 interaction
Just set the identifier and or
在递交 interaction 前
group identifier before donating
设定标识符或组识别符
Then, when you want to delete
当你想要删除时
it, you call delete with an
你可以调用 delete
array of the identifiers that
并填入你想删除的标识符阵列
You can also delete all donated
你还可以通过调用delete
intents with a shared group
并填入组标识符
identifier by calling delete
删除所有拥有
with the group identifier.
同样组标识符的已递交 Intent
And, finally, just like
最后 就如
NSUserActivity, there is a way
NSUserActivity 一样
to delete all your donated
有一种可以删除
intents by calling deleteAll on
所有你递交的 Intent 的方法
INInteraction.
即在 INInteraction 调用 deleteAll
Please make sure to delete your
请确保在合适的时机
donations at the appropriate
并填入你想删除的 Donation
This will give your users the
这会给你的用户
best possible suggestions and
最好的建议
never make them wonder why
也不会让他们思考
they're seeing suggestions for
为什么会给他们建议
things that are no longer
与他们毫无关联的信息
So, now that we've looked at
我们已经观看了
different things to consider
在创造和递交捷径时
when creating and donating
应该考虑的事情
shortcuts, let's end by briefly
让我们最后简单地
looking at what you can use to
看一下怎么创造
create the best possible media
最好的媒体捷径
We created a new intent that
我们创建了一个与捷径
works great with Shortcuts.
配合很好的新 Intent
This intent is called
这个 Intent 被称作
INPlayMediaIntent and allows you
INPlayMediaIntent
to create and donate shortcuts
它可以允许你创建和递交
to play audio or video content.
可以播放音频或视频内容的捷径
When handling this intent in
处理扩展中的 Intent 时
your extension, you can choose
你可以选择
to have it handled by your app
在你的 App 后台处理它
This allows you to start audio
这可以让你直接从你的 App
playback straight from your app.
开始音频播放
Besides being suggested in
除了在搜索界面
search and on the lock screen,
或者锁定屏幕上被建议
shortcuts with this intent will
拥有这个 Intent 的捷径
also be suggested in the
也应该在用户
playback controls on the lock
连接耳机时
screen when the user connects
在锁定屏幕上被播放控制所推荐
their headphones, making it even
这样用户可以
easier for them to start
更容易地
listening to your content.
听到你的内容
And, finally, shortcuts with
最后 拥有这个 Intent 的捷径
this intent work great on the
在 HomePod 上
HomePod.
也运行得很好
Just add a play media shortcut
只需要在你的 iPhone 上
to Siri on your iPhone and
对 Siri 增加一个播放媒体的捷径
invoke it on your HomePod.
然后在你的 HomePod 上唤醒它
The audio will start playing
这个音频就会在你的手机上
from your phone through HomePod.
通过 HomePod 播放
We also created a new API that
我们还创建了一个新 API
allows you tell the system about
来让你能告诉系统
new content they might be
它可能会感兴趣的内容
This is great for periodical
这对于周期性的内容来说
content, where the content that
非常棒
you would want to be suggested
因为你想要建议给用户的
to your users isn't something
是他们之前没有听过或看过的内容
So, those are a couple of things
这里有一些我们为了
that we have added to make great
制作好的媒体捷径
media shortcuts.
而增加的东西
Now, let's summarize what we
现在 让我们总结一下
just talked about.
刚刚说的内容
Shortcuts enable powerful, new
捷径可以让你的 App
experiences with your apps.
有着强有力的 全新的体验
It provides new ways to engage
它通过将你的 App
your users by exposing your app
在不同的地方连通
throughout the system in a
从而为吸引用户提供了
variety of places.
一个新方法
So, just search the lock screen,
比如在搜索界面上 在锁定屏幕上
the Siri Watch Face on your
在 Apple Watch 上的 Siri 表盘上
Apple Watch, and in Siri itself.
以及通过 Siri 自身搜索
You can also use it in the new
你可以在新的捷径 App 中使用它
You can adopt shortcuts by using
你可以通过使用 NSUserActivity
NSUserActivity, which is a
来采用捷径
really easy way to expose the
这是一种展示 App 内容的
content of your app.
简单方法
Or you can use intents which
你还可以采用与系统
provides you with a deeper
有更深的融合的 Intent
integration in the system and
从而为你的用户
can unlock entirely new
解锁一个
experiences for your users.
全新的体验
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
For more information, our
如果想要了解更多的信息
session is 211, and you can find
我们的会议号码是 211 你可以在
our page on developer.apple.com.
developer.Apple.com 上找到我们的页面
You can also find us in the labs
你还可以在这周内
throughout the week.
去我们的实验室找我们
Thank you so much for coming.
感谢你的聆听
And we can't wait to see what
我们迫不及待地想要看到
shortcuts you'll create.
你创建的捷径
Enjoy the rest of your
祝你在接下来的会议愉快
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]